Alfredo Alcalá

IT and Application Specialist

With +12 years in the technology area, I am characterized by being a person focused on continuing to obtain knowledge in order to generate a greater contribution to my projects. Skills include networking, security, analytical thinking, and creative problem-solving. Able to apply customer service concepts to IT to improve the user experience for customers, employees, and management.



Pagota, Colombia

+57 319 392 7070

in linkedin.com/in/alfredo-a-567b91196

EXPERIENCE

Application SpecialistNetcom Wireless SA

10/2017 - 12/2020

Functions

- Coordinate with senior-level analysts and assist end-users and stakeholders to resolve and layout required information infrastructure.
- Develop, implement and optimize stored procedures and functions using T-SOL.
- Suggest new queries. Analyze existing SQL queries for performance improvements.
- Collaborate with developers and vendors to secure infrastructure being developed for end-user needs and ensure achievement of all business objectives.
- Assist with system check and quality assurance. Work with aid end users and provide support to infrastructure facilities and ensure smooth adoption.
- Administer application and provide technical expertise in development and execution of all IT systems.
- Verifying the security of third-party vendors and collaborating with them to meet security requirements

Support Specialist II Latcom SA

06/2017 - 09/2017

Functions

- Telephone support in internal campaigns, management and escalation of Level II cases.
- Smartphone Equipment configuration.
- Management advice and support of PQR, provide support for correction and detection of failures in their connection to the data network.
- Preparation of management and performance reports.

Support Analyst Avior Airlines CA

02/2016 - 05/2017

Functions

- Installing and maintaining computer systems and networks.maintaining records of repairs, fixes, and maintenance
- Setting up computer workstations, including peripheral devices and troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve computer problems
- Ensuring security and privacy of networks and computers
- Organizing and scheduling upgrades and maintenance so that others can continue working uninterrupted

SKILLS

Coding Communication Security Networking

Analytics Reporting

EDUCATION

Associate's degree in Informatics
University institute of industrial technology
Rodolfo Loero Arismendi

2007 - 2011

CERTIFICATES

IBM CyberSecurity Analyst

Google IT Support

Google

Open Source Software Development, Linux and Git The linux Foundation

JavaScript, JQuery and JSON

University of Michigan

Introduction to Data Analitics for Bussines

University of Colorado Boulder

INTEREST

